A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 6262-9286 FA739C
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Anthropological perspectives on development in the Kumaun and Garhwah Regions of India (Reports 006930), 1976 (Box 309)
  Anthropological perspectives on development in India ...
  Anthropology -- Research -- India; Peasantry -- Research -- India; Mailloux, Laurie
- The role of models in the decision process in agriculture (Reports 006931), 1976 (Box 309)
  34 p. + appendix
  Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Developing countries; Agriculture -- Social aspects -- Developing countries; Agriculture and state -- Developing countries; Petit, Michel, 1936-
- Toward a program in public planning and management in India (Reports 006932), 1976 (Box 310)
  Social planning -- India; Central planning -- India; Regional planning -- India; Urban planning and research -- India; Geithner, Peter F.; Row, Arthur T.; Pande, Vijay G.; Gwatkin, Davidson R.; Chowdhry, Kamla, 1920-2006; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- The Upper Division Scholarship Program: an interim report on the pilot program in Illinois and Michigan, 1970-1972 (Reports 006933) (Box 310)
  Education and Research/Higher Education & Research
  9 p. + appendices.
  Minority students -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Scholarships -- Illinois; Scholarships -- Michigan; Scholarships -- United States; Education, Higher -- United States -- Finance; Sabine, Gordon A.; Ford Foundation. Higher Education and Research
- An evaluation of the Program Associates Program (Reports 006934), 1971 (Box 310)
  06990507
  Employment of Indian program associates to support staff development program of the Government of India's Department of Family Planning.
  Birth control -- India; Population assistance -- India; Ghosh, Bimal; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- End of assignment report on cultural programs in India (Reports 006935), 1970 (Box 310)
  Report on what the author believes was a successful decision of the Foundation to support selected cultural projects in India.
  Cultural programs in India...
  Cultural property -- Protection -- India; Endowments -- India -- Evaluation; Isenberg, Arthur; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Report on visit to India, September 1968, as Ford Foundation consultant on proposed research project to study Indian entrepreneurship (Reports 006936) (Box 310)
  Memo to Douglas Ensminger about the value of researching Indian entrepreneurship and business practices and values in India.
  06200299
  The Regents of the University Of California, Berkeley
  Felowship program in economic development and administration.
  Entrepreneurship -- Research -- India; Business -- India; Broehl, Wayne G.; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Possible Ford Foundation assistance to pilot projects in occupational education (Reports 006937), 1971 (Box 310)
  Memo to S. N. Saraf, dated January 25, 1971.
  Vocational education -- India; Occupational training -- India; Education, Secondary -- India; Educational assistance -- India; Staley, Eugene, 1906-1989; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Recommendations for strengthening the academic program at Chetana College, Bombay (Reports 006938), 1970 (Box 310)
  Memo to Harold Howe on recommendations for improving Chetana College.
  17 p. + appendices: tables
  Education, Higher -- India; Vocational education -- India; Occupational training -- India; Kunsela, William R.; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific; Chetana College (Bombay, India)
- Report of the visit abroad of Professor Dool Singh (Reports 006939), 1969 (Box 310)
  Dool Singh is head of the Dept. of Business Administration at Birla Institute of Technology and Science, Pilani, Rajasthan, India. Visit took place March 25 to July 14, 1969. Report of Professor Singh's visit to the United States and participation in a se
  06990299
  18 p. + appendix.
  Business -- Study and teaching; Singh, Dool
- Rural wheat storage in Ludhiana District, Punjab (Reports 006940), 1970 (Box 310)
  Report demonstrates an approach to evaluate the field problems of rural grain storage in a limited area having a variety of new and old grain protection practices available.
  28, 12 p. + appendices: ill., tables, charts
  Wheat -- Storage -- India; Grain -- Storage -- India; Willson, Harold R. (Harold Rossen), 1941-; Singh, Amar; Bindra, O. S.; Everett, Travis R.; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific; Ford Foundation. Field Office New Delhi
- Observations on the Tenth Pacific Trade and Development Conference (PTDC), Canberra, Australia, March 19-23, 1979 (Reports 006941) (Box 310)
  Pacific Trade and Development Conference (10th:1979: Australian National University)
  International trade -- Congresses; Agriculture and state -- Congresses; Agricultural assistance -- Congresses; Remenyi, J. V.
- Remarks prepared for delivery by John Bresnan of the Ford Foundation at a Trilateral Commission Symposium on Expanding Food Production in South and Southeast Asia, Tokyo, November 27-28 (Reports 006942), 1978 (Box 310)
  Food supply -- South Asia -- Speeches, addresses, etc.; Food supply -- Southeast Asia -- -- Speeches, addresses, etc.; Bresnan, John, 1927-2006
- Research Institute for Higher Education, Hiroshima University (Reports 006943), 1977 (Box 310)
  International Division/Higher Education and Research
  Education, Higher -- Research -- Japan; Universities and colleges -- Japan; Passin, Herbert; Ford Foundation. Higher Education and Research; Hiroshima Daigaku
- On the computer problems of IPB and BPS (Reports 006944), 1977 (Box 310)
  Report on the computer capabilities of the Institute of Agriculture in Bogol and the Central Bureau of Statistics in Indonesia.
  Computers -- Study and teaching -- Japan; Computers -- Purchasing -- Japan; International cooperation; Sugiura, Ippei, 1925-
- Discussion on archaeological training, Manila (Reports 006945), 1979 (Box 310)
  Memo to John Cool, dated January 24, 1979.
  Archaeological training in Manila ...
  Archaeology -- Study and teaching -- Philippines; Anthropology -- Study and teaching -- Philippines; Museum techniques -- Study and teaching -- Philippines; Lyons, Elizabeth; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- India's new departures in mass motivation for fertility control (Reports 006946), 1968 (Box 310)
  Discusses the need for the use of the mass media to instill motivation for population control in India.
  Birth control -- India; Communication in birth control -- India; Fertility, Human -- India; Mass media -- India; Wilder, Frank, 1920-; Tyagi, D. K. (Dinesh K.)
- How do people adopt new birth control practices? (Reports 006947), 1968 (Box 310)
  "Prepared ... for the Institutional Workshop on Communications Aspects of National Family Planning Programs, Bangkok, Thailand, December 2-14, 1968." --p.1.
  Communication in birth control -- Developing countries -- Congresses; Birth control -- Developing countries -- Congresses; Birth control -- Social aspects -- Developing countries; Fertility, Human -- Social aspects -- Developing countries -- Congresses; Saunders, Lyle; Ford Foundation. Population Program
- Communications for information and motivation in family planning (Reports 006948), 1966 (Box 310)
  Prepared ...for the Advisory Committee on the Application of Science and Technology to Development of the U. N. Economic and Social Council... --T.p.
  Communication in birth control -- Developing countries; Birth control -- Social aspects -- Developing countries; Fertility, Human -- Social aspects -- Developing countries; Ford Foundation. Population Program
- Communication research and family planning in India (Reports 006949), 1970 (Box 310)
  Memo to Pratap Kapur to review priority areas of needed research on family planning communication and to outline procedures by which research on this topic can be utilized more completely in making population policy decisions in India.
  18 p.: ill.
  Communication research and family planning in India
  Communication in birth control -- India -- Evaluation; Birth control -- India; Communications -- Research -- India; Rogers, Everett M.; Ford Foundation. Population Program
- Assessing the needs of family planning information, education and communications programs (Reports 006950), 1972 (Box 310)
  Birth control -- Research -- Nigeria; Communication in birth control -- Nigeria; Population assistance -- Nigeria; De Pietro, Rocco A.; Ford Foundation. Population Program
- Mass communications: easier said than done -- but do-able (Reports 006951), 1968 (Box 310)
  A discussion paper prepared for the Ford Foundation ... --p. 11.
  [7 p.]
  Communication in birth control -- Developing countries; Birth control -- Developing countries; Wilder, Frank, 1920-; Ford Foundation. Population Program
- A brief survey of art and archaeology in Sri Lanka, 1979 (Reports 006952) (Box 310)
  File memo dated February 19, 1979.
  7 p. + attachment.
  Art and archaeology in Sri Lanka ...
  Art -- Study and teaching -- Sri Lanka; Archaeology -- Study and teaching -- Sri Lanka; Cultural property -- Protection -- Sri Lanka; Lyons, Elizabeth; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Indicators of impact in family planning communications research projects (Reports 006953), 1962 (Box 310)
  From Family planning news, Vol. 3, No. 8. A review of the need for criteria to evaluate the success of family planning communications research projects.
  [9] p.
  Communication in birth control -- Research -- India; Birth control -- Research -- India; Saunders, Lyle
- Press workbook for communication in family planning (Reports 006954), 1971 (Box 310)
  53 p.
  Communication in birth control -- Developing countries; Birth control -- Social aspects -- Developing countries; De Pietro, Rocco A.; Ford Foundation. Population Program
- Population study in Central America (Reports 006955), 1966 (Box 310)
  Population research -- Central America; Birth control -- Research -- Central America; Saunders, Lyle; Trowbridge, James W.; Ford Foundation. Population Program
- Press use for family planning (Reports 006956), 1972 (Box 310)
  84 p. -- 28 cm.
  Communication in birth control -- Nigeria; Mass media in birth control -- Nigeria; Birth control -- Nigeria; De Pietro, Rocco A.; Ford Foundation. Population Program
- Population: Central America (Reports 006957), 1966 (Box 310)
  Birth control -- Central America; Population policy -- Central America; Population assistance -- Central America; Saunders, Lyle; Samora, Julian, 1920-1996
- Communications program planning needs which can be fulfilled by library and information services (Reports 006958), 1972 (Box 310)
  Paper prepared for the Fifth National Conference on Population/Family Planning Library and Information Services.
  Communication in birth control; Birth control -- Study and teaching; Libraries and education; Sweeney, William O., 1931-
- Education research: the promise and the problem (Reports 006959), 1976 (Box 310)
  Remarks at meeting of the A.E.R.A., April 21, 1976, San Francisco.
  22 p. -- 28 cm
  Education -- Study and teaching; Howe, Harold, 1918-2002; American Educational Research Association; American Educational Research Association
- Case study: planning Nigeria's first public information campaign for family planning (Reports 006960), 1972 (Box 310)
  L72-173
  PAPER Conference (1972 June 12-16: Helsinger, Denmark)
  Population -- Congresses; De Pietro, Rocco A.
- Conference on the Third World and the role of press (Reports 006961), 1977 (Box 310)
  Memo dated May 26, 1977.
  Press -- Developing countries; Journalism -- Developing countries; Freedom of the press -- Developing countries; Davis, David M. (David McFarland), 1926-2007; Ford Foundation. International Division
- Family life survey (Reports 006962), 1972 (Box 310)
  1 v.: var. pag.: tables, forms -- 28 cm.
  Family -- Nigeria; Birth control -- Nigeria; De Pietro, Rocco A.; Overseas Economic Development (Nigeria) Ltd.; Overseas Economic Development (Nigeria) Ltd.; Ford Foundation. Population Program
- Computer technology developments in Philippines (Reports 006963), 1970 (Box 310)
  07000212
  Economic Commission For Asia and the Far East
  Training workshops on computer processing for th 1970 Asian censuses.
  35 leaves: tables -- 28 cm.
  Computer programs -- Study and teaching -- Philippines; Census -- Philippines -- Statistics; Housing -- Philippines -- Statistics; Lackner, M. R.; Ford Foundation. Population Program; United Nations. Economic Commission for Asia and the Far East
- Organizational structure: Office of Logistical Services, Division of Administration (Reports 006964), 1978 (Box 311)
  1 v.: var. pag: tables -- 28 cm.
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Administration; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Cost of operation; Ford Foundation
- A study in neglect: a report on women prisoners, July 15, 1972 - Octoer 15 (Reports 006965) (Box 311)
  Submitted to the Women's Prison Association.
  L72-117.
  44 p. + appendices -- 28 cm.
  Women prisoners; Hendrix, Omar; Women's Prison Association of New York; Women's Prison Association of New York
- Reflections on a multi-racial society (Reports 006966), 1982 (Box 311)
  Transcript speech prepared for the Granada Lecture Series, November 1, 1982.
  34 p. -- 28 cm.
  Race awareness -- United States; Race discrimination -- United States; Minorities -- United States -- Social conditions; Thomas, Franklin A.; Ford Foundation. National Affairs
- Review of Foundation programs concerned with economic development in the rural South (Reports 006967), 1971 (Box 311)
  57 p. + appendices: tables -- 28 cm.
  Rural development -- Southern States; Rural development -- United States; Heaps, David; Ford Foundation. National Affairs
- AID project: farm development in the North-west Frontier Province of Pakistan (Reports 006968), 1974 (Box 311)
  Report to the Maize and Millets Research Institute, Nowshera, North West Frontier Province, following a visit to Pakistan June-July 1974.
  PA660-0446c.
  10 p. + appendices --28 cm.
  Corn -- Research -- North-west Frontier Province (Pakistan); Millets -- Research -- North-west Frontier Province (Pakistan); Agriculture -- Research -- North-west Frontier Province (Pakistan); Agricultural development projects -- North-west Frontier Province; McKay, M. E.; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Report on maize in the Punjab (Reports 006969), 1973 (Box 311)
  Prepared for the Secretary of Agriculture, Punjab. (See also Report on maize in the N.W.F.P.).
  Corn -- India -- Punjab (India); Sprague, Ernest Warren, 1925-
- Report on maize in the N.W.F.P. North-West Frontier Province of Pakistan (Reports 006970), 1973 (Box 311)
  Prepared for the Secretary of Agriculture, NWFP. (See also Report on maize in the Punjab).
  06600446
  Centro Internacional de Mejoramiento de Maiz y Trigo
  Strengthening agricultural institutes for wheat research in West Pakistan.
  Corn -- Research -- North-west Frontier Province (Pakistan); Millets -- Research -- North-west Frontier Province (Pakistan); Agricultural development projects -- North-west Frontier Province (Pakistan); Agricultural productivity -- Pakistan; Sprague, Ernest Warren, 1925-; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific; International Maize and Wheat Improvement Center
- Possible participation by Australian government in maize and millets research (Reports 006971), 1973 (Box 311)
  Report to the Maize & Millets Research Institute, Nowshera, North West Frontier Province, following a visit to Pakistan, February 6-9, 1973.
  8 p. + appendices -- 28 cm.
  Agricultural engineering -- Study and teaching -- Australia; Agriculture -- Research -- North-west Frontier Province (Pakistan); Turner, A. Keith, 1941-; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific; International Maize and Wheat Improvement Center
- Proposed plans for the development of the Maize and Millets Research Institute (MMRI), Nowshera, N.W.F.P. North-West Frontier Province of Pakistan (Reports 006972), 1973 (Box 311)
  Report to the Secretary of Agriculture, Government of the N.W.F.P., Peshawar.
  12 p. -- 28 cm.
  Corn -- Research -- North-west Frontier Province (Pakistan); Millets -- Research -- North-west Frontier Province (Pakistan); Agricultural development projects -- North-west Frontier Province (Pakistan); Stewart, John A.; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific; International Maize and Wheat Improvement Center
- Prospects for accelerating maize and millets production in the Himalayan Region (Reports 006973), 1971 (Box 311)
  Strengthening agricultural institutes in wheat research in West Pakistan.
  4 leaves + appendix: table -- 28 cm.
  Agricultural productivity -- North-west Frontier Province (Pakistan); Crop yield -- North-west Frontier Province (Pakistan); Agriculture -- Research -- North-west Frontier Province (Pakistan); Sprague, Ernest Warren, 1925-; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific; International Maize and Wheat Improvement Center
- Maize and millets research in the Punjab (Reports 006974), 1971 (Box 311)
  Prepared for the Secretary of Agriculture, Government of the Punjab, Lahore. Discusses the creation of a Maize and Millet Research Institute in Punjab.
  11 p. + annexes: tables -- 28 cm.
  Corn -- Research -- Pakistan; Millets -- Research -- Pakistan; Agriculture -- Research -- Pakistan; Sprague, Ernest Warren, 1925-; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific; International Maize and Wheat Improvement Center
- The Green Revolution is not dead (Reports 006975), 1970 (Box 311)
  Green Revolution; Wheat -- Yields; Wheat -- Research; Crop yields; Agricultural productivity; Borlaug, Norman E. (Norman Ernest), 1914-2009; Narvaez Morales, Ignacio; International Maize and Wheat Improvement Center
- Employment of local nationals on Ford Foundation projects (Reports 006976), 1965 (Box 311)
  Discussion of the proposal to hire local nationals for agricultural development projects in Pakistan. Notes that this idea was employed with success in India.
  06500380
  Government of Pakistan
  Training institutes for the agricultural extension service in Pakistan
  Agricultural extension workers -- Training of -- Pakistan; Agricultural extension work -- Pakistan; Davy, Dorcey F.; Ford Foundation
- End of tour report (Reports 006977), 1969 (Box 311)
  Report on agricultural mechanization in West Pakistan.
  Training instiutes for agricultural extension service in Pakistan.
  Agricultural extension work -- Pakistan; Agricultural mechanics -- Pakistan; Giles, G. W. (George Wallace), 1910-2003; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific; Pakistan
- Licensing policies and prices: Structure of farm tractors (Reports 006978), 1969 (Box 311)
  Training institutes for agricultural extension service in Pakistan.
  10 p. -- 33 cm.
  Tractors -- Pakistan -- Licenses; Tractors -- Law and legislation -- Pakistan; Agricultural mechanics -- Pakistan; Giles, G. W. (George Wallace), 1910-2003; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific; Pakistan
- The practicalities of tractor vs. no-tractor mechanization (Reports 006979), 1969 (Box 311)
  Discussion of the benefits and drawbacks of agricultural mechanization including tractors. Followed by Comments on the draft "Education and training" by Ghulam Sarwar Sheikh and A.N. Kazi.
  7 p. + appendices.
  Farm mechanization -- Pakistan; Giles, G. W. (George Wallace), 1910-2003; Pakistan
- Preliminary note contributing to the subjects of manufacturing (Chapter XI), research and extension (Chapter XVI) using the harvesting and threshing of wheat as an example (Reports 006980), 1969 (Box 311)
  Discusses new dimensions in the problems with mechanized harvesting and threshing of wheat in West Pakistan.
  8 p. + appendices.
  Wheat -- Harvesting -- Pakistan -- West Pakistan; Wheat -- Threshing -- Pakistan -- West Pakistan; Giles, G. W. (George Wallace), 1910-2003; Pakistan
- Several second generation opportunities (Reports 006981), 1970 (Box 311)
  Report on agriculture in Pakistan.
  Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Pakistan; Food supply -- Pakistan; Agricultural extension work -- Pakistan; Davy, Dorcey F.; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific; Pakistan
- Notes on modern rice mills program in India (Reports 006982), 1968 (Box 311)
  Discussion of the introduction of modern rice milling practices in India.
  Rice -- Milling -- India; Wimberly, James E.; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific; Pakistan
- Recommendations for the establishment of a Rice Engineering Centre (Reports 006983), 1966 (Box 311)
  Prepared for the government of India by consultant team, Louisiana State University Rice Experiment Station.
  31 p. -- 28 cm.
  Rice -- Research -- India; Rice -- Milling -- India; Wimberly, James E.; Faulkner, Macon D.; Caffey, H. Rouse (Horace Rouse), 1929-2012; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific; Louisiana State University (Baton Rouge, La.). Rice Experiment Station; Pakistan
- Paddy drying equipment for the Tanjore Paddy Project (Reports 006984), 1968 (Box 311)
  Presented to the Indian Society of Agricultural Engineers, Dec. 1967, at the University of Agricultural sciences, Bangalore. Discusses a plan to process rice which is harvested during the monsoon season.
  Rice -- Processing -- India; Wimberly, James E.; Pakistan
- New trends in milling and processing (Reports 006985), 1968 (Box 311)
  Discussion of the new trends in rice milling and processing in India, thanks to seven modern rice mills.
  Rice -- Milling -- India; Rice -- Processing -- India; Wimberly, James E.; Pakistan
- Necessary ingredients for policy research in Asia (Reports 006986), 1966 (Box 311)
  06590241
  Advisors and consultants for the Planning adn Evaluation Unit, Department of Agriculture, Government of Pakistan.
  Agriculture and politics -- Asia; Agriculture and state -- Asia; Politics, Practical -- Asia; Weisblat, A. M. (Abraham M.); Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific; Foundation-Administered Project (FAP)
- Agricultural development in West Pakistan (Reports 006987), 1964 (Box 311)
  Review of performance of agricultural production in the Second Plan, 1960-1965.
  International Division/Asia and the Pacific;Office of the Vice President
  Agricultural development projects -- Pakistan -- West Pakistan; Agricultural productivity -- Pakistan -- West Pakistan; Aresvik, Oddvar, 1915-
- Later-generation agricultural problems (Reports 006988), 1966 (Box 311)
  "Prepared for conference on agricultural development, Bellagio, Italy, April 23-5, 1969." --p.1.
  Advisors and consultants for the Planning and Evaluation Unit, Department of Agriculture, Government of Pakistan.
  Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Developing countries; Agriculture and state -- Developing countries; Hardin, Lowell Stewart, 1917-; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific; Foundation-Administered Project (FAP)
- Some social aspects of population control (Reports 006989), 1971 (Box 311)
  Reprinted from the Journal of the Christian Medical Association of India, October 1971, Vol. XLVI, No. 10.
  Birth control -- Social aspects -- India; Cool, John C., 1926-; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- The Second India study series: Concept and objectives: A summary prepared for presentation to the Eighth Research Seminar in Population Planning, Peshawar (Reports 006990), 1974 (Box 311)
  Prepared for presentation to the Eighth Research Seminar in Population Planning, Peshawar, April 18-20, 1974. Discussion of a series of studies designed to draw together data and to assess the probable impact of continued high population growth in India.
  Birth control -- India; Cool, John C., 1926-; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Tanzania's road to development: bringing development to the people (Reports 006991), 1974 (Box 311)
  Interview of Paul Bomani, Ambassador of the United Republic of Tanzania to the United States;reprint from International development review, 1974/2.
  07400076
  The Pakistan Academy for Rural Development